Mike Trumbell

About

I'm a FinTech professional with over 10 years of experience building applications. I've worked with many types of software including REST APIs, mobile apps, web apps and back office enterprise solutions. I bring a unique perspective to a development team and my diverse background allows me to solve a wide range of difficult problems through software.

Experience

Software Engineering Lead, Vela/OptionsCity, Chicago, IL, 2015-Present

- Led the successful migration from the legacy Windows application to the EmberJS multiplatform CityTrader application (Electron)
- Built a multi-device (Android and iOS) mobile application that reused many of our web components
- Mentored 2 developers (EmberJS and Django) in building and maintaining 5 different production applications and organizing quarterly goals
- Managed weekly releases to our client applications including writing release notes and notifying high profile customers of large changes
- Built several API (Scala) features including a new permission framework which closely resembles the Django permissions model
- Successfully satisfied a CME market data entitlements audit by organizing years worth of subscription data from both the City and Metro platforms

Software Engineer, OptionsCity, Chicago, IL, 2011-2015

- Designed and implemented the internal support and CRM application which helps
 managed releases, track customer data, track server specs and automates dozens of
 processes (SupportServices written in Django and JavaScript)
- Interviewed support staff to add features to quickly turn around common support requests
- · Designed externally facing risk portal to allow Risk Admins to manage trader risk
- Built a jobs framework using Celery to allow support staff to easily configure complex jobs in the web interface

Software Engineer, TradeForecaster, Chicago, IL, 2009-2011

- · Added features to Django/JavaScript application for administering trading platforms
- Streamlined commercial trader signup process
- · Administered all database migrations
- · Built custom reports and tools for traders
- · Automated dozens of tasks

Application Support Engineer, TradeForecaster, Chicago, IL, 2008-2009

- Built and maintained hardware for low latency performance trading
- · Led classes at the CBOT teaching traders how to use our platform
- Administered farm of servers and ensured application health through monitoring
- · Fielded support calls from commercial traders
- · Wrote scripts to automate management and debugging of applications

Skills

Technical

- JavaScript (EmberJS, JQuery)
- · Python/Django
- · Scala/Play

Distributed Systems

- · Web development
- Mobile development
- REST APIs
- Cloud configuration (AWS)

Databases

- SQL (MySQL, PostGreSQL)
- MongoDB
- Google Firebase

Education

Central Michigan University - Management Information Systems, 2006